Sam Hains CV

samhains.com sam@samhains.com 646 799 5400

Artist and A/V technologist. Experienced with visual design, content creation, 3d graphics and animation pipeline, server programming, projection design, machine learning and data visualization. Creating experiences with Unity, Cinema4D, Houdini, Adobe suite, TouchDesigner, Python and openFrameworks.

Selected Work

Small mirrors of the real – article published in NYU ITP's Adjacent journal

itp.nyu.edu/adjacent/issue-5/small-mirrors-of-thereal/

Zero Likes research project – using deep learning and • Focusing on using technology in the context of computer vision technology to explore abstract, human questions

creators.vice.com/en au/article/z4jz3x/this-aicreates-art-from-instagram-posts-with-zero-likes samhains.com/zero-likes

QWERTY SYSTEMS - A voice controlled video installation and performance system performed at Culture Hub and ISSUE Project Room samhains.com/qwerty-systems

Volvox Nylon – VFX content for moving image commission for NYLON Beauty Innovator Awards. Content designed and installed on immersive 360 dome projection

samhains.com/volvox-labs

2077: Open Web Archive - An interactive, voicecontrolled art installation built with Touch Designer and python

samhains.com/2077-open-web-archive

Employment

#DateMe - Off Broadway (Projections & Interconnectivity Design) (March-Current)

Volvox Labs (VFX & Creative Technology Intern) (June-Aug 2018)

School for Poetic Computation (Teaching Assistant) (February-2018)

Freelance (A/V Technologist) (March-2018 - Present)

KindyNow (Software Developer) (Mar 2016 - March 2017)

Inlight Media (Software Developer) (Nov 2015 – Mar 2016)

Aeon Magazine (Software Developer & Designer) (May 2015 - Nov 2015)

Education

M.P.S (Tisch, Interactive Telecommunications Program) (September 2017-Current)

New York University, NY

video performance and art installation.

Creative Research Residency (April 2017)

School of Ma, Belgrade

• Researched, and developed works relating to the state of the art in Deep learning, machine learning and computer vision technologies.

Master of Engineering (Software) (2014)

University Of Melbourne, Melbourne Discontinued

Bachelor of Commerce (Management) (2010-

University Of Melbourne, Melbourne Completed 2013

References

Andrew Lazarow

Designer and A/V technologist ajlazarow@gmail.com

Gene Kogan

Educator and Machine Learning expert kogan.gene@gmail.com